本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： Nick冰 熊猫大虾 Danky Shadow Cinderella
校对： Cinderella    后期： 泡面小小
我觉得你丈夫调查的事情仍在进行
I think Something your husband was investigating could still be in play.
所以这有可能和他被谋杀有关系?
So this could have something to do with his murder?
这是詹姆斯・林 是吗?
Well, that's James Lim, right?
他是个商人
He's a businessman on his way up.
还有他兄弟林杰志是资深的工会领袖
Oh, and his brother's Lim Chee Kit, the senior union leader.
关于温斯顿的谋杀案 李库方是嫌疑人之一
Winston's murder... Lee-Kum Fong was one of the suspects.
当晚有人看见他在现场
He was seen in the area that night.
请代我问候郑夫人
Please pass on my respects to Mrs Cheng.
温斯顿在这个社区很受人尊敬
Winston was a much respected man in this community
他的死也是我们的损失
and her loss is our loss.
我生了他的孩子 是个男孩 现在已经四岁了
I had his baby. A boy. He's four now.
你要我为你在中情局做间谍?
You want me to spy on the CIA for you?
我得闯进怀尔德・比尔的办公室
I'd have to break into Wild Bill's office.
这个任务对你来说肯定不在话下
A challenge surely within your skill set.
弗兰克 我喜欢上别人了 我要搬出去了
Frank, I've met someone. I'm moving out.
这行不通的 你不属于这里
It's not gonna work. You don't belong here.
别离开弗兰克 你还没告诉他吧?
Don't leave Frank. You haven't told him yet?
接下来 就是所谓的外交事件了
Now, there's what you call a diplomatic incident.
要是你想跟小白脸鬼混
If you're going to go wild with the pool boy,
老天 可千万别告诉你丈夫
for God's sake don't tell the husband.
你在看什么呢?
What are you looking at?
你以前没见过我下厨吗?
You've never seen me cook before?
我正要出去 看不了多久了
Just heading out. I won't be long.
你要去哪?
Wait. Where are you going?
见个客户 我没跟你说吗?
A client. Didn't I tell you?
没有啊 你姐姐和你侄女要来
No, you didn't. Your sister is coming with your niece.
- 你得待在家 - 亲爱的 我必须去
- You have to stay. - Baby, I have to go.
这件事非常重要
This is really important.
做好我最爱的蛋羹 我会在九点的时候回来
Make my favourite egg custard. I'll be back at nine.
你知道我吃蛋羹的时候会发生什么
You know what happens when I eat your custard.
打扮一下 我们去拉斐尔跳个通宵
Dress up and we'll go to Raffles and dance all night.
你能把黄莺带进来吗?
Oh, can you bring the songbirds in?
我会带进来 然后煮了它们当晚饭
I'll bring the songbirds in and I'll cook them for dinner.
我爱你 希望你相信这一点
I love you. I hope you have no doubts about that.
走吧! 走走走
Go on! Just go.
九点前要回来哦
Be back before nine, now.
石龙岗之路 第一季第10集
我不知道你是怎么想的 你竟然放了他
I don't know what you think you're gonna get out of him.
- 他不会坦白的 - 为什么?
- He won't just confess. - Why not?
他已经参加过一次谋杀了
He's already up for one murder.
他们又不会吊死他两次
They won't hang him twice.
要是他坦白自己杀了温斯顿
He could do a deal with his lawyer
他可以和律师做个交易
if he confesses to killing Winston.
他们可以帮他免除死刑
They could waive the death penalty.
郑夫人会同意吗?
Is that what Mrs Cheng wants?
让杀她丈夫的凶手免于死刑?
Her husband's killer not to hang?
另外 我们也不是很确定他就是凶手
Besides, we're not too sure he's the killer.
他还只是嫌疑人
He's still a suspect.
让我们弄个水落石出
Let's find out.
他在哪?
Where is he?
李库方人呢?
我们知道郑叔叔曾为他的生命担忧
So, we know Uncle Cheng feared for his life
他也意识到自己被跟踪了
and he was being followed.
而且 这个案子的文件也丢了
Also, the case file's missing.
现在方出狱了 有人保释了他
And now Fong's been let out of jail, so someone put up the bail,
但他的律师不会说是谁保释的
but his lawyer won't say who.
有人在保护他而且试图隐藏什么
Someone is trying to hide something and is protecting him.
那现在怎么办?
So now what?
我们怎么找出当事人和他的目的?
How do we find out who or why?
我们要查出那天晚上他见的是谁
We've got to find out who he was meeting that night.
也许我们可以回想他的路线
Maybe we can retrace his footsteps.
他傍晚的时候去见了一个客户
Well, he left just on dark to meet with a client.
是的 我记得 他带着公文包
Yeah, I remember. He had a briefcase.
山姆 你忙吗?
Sam, are you busy?
我要去取点东西 然后去见康 怎么了?
Got to pick something up. Then I'm meeting Kang. Why?
- 没什么 - 要帮忙吗?
- That's fine. - Need a hand?
就是有个会 没什么事
It's just a meeting. It's fine.
只是... 看起来没什么危险
It just... it didn't seem dangerous.
没提到什么会议
No mention of a meeting.
- 其实我们知道他先去了哪里 - 哪里?
- We do know where he went first. - Where?
- 他去见了一个... 朋友 - 谁?
- He went to see a... friend. - Who?
你温斯顿叔叔... 还有一个家庭
Your Uncle Winston... had another family.
什么?
What?
- 阿姨 对不起 - 没事
- Aunty, I'm so sorry. - Yeah.
阿姨
Aunty.
- 他喜欢新学校吗? - 很喜欢 谢谢你
- How does he like his new school? - He loves it. Thank you.
希望打疫苗不会很痛
And the vaccine I hope didn't hurt him too much.
美玲 我们过来是因为
Mei Ling, we're here because we need to
我们要追溯温斯顿去世前的事情
trace back Winston's last moments.
你能想起什么吗?
Can you think of anything?
他要去见一个客户
He was meeting with a client
但我们不确定他有没有见到
but we're just not sure whether he met with him or not.
嗯 他确实说要去见一个人
Well, he did say he was meeting someone.
所以不能留在这 我当时很生气
That's why he couldn't stay. I got really upset.
就这时候他给了我这块表
That's when he gave me the watch.
要是出了什么意外 把这个给我妻子
If something goes wrong, give this to my wife.
我知道这要求有点过分
I know that's a lot to ask.
确实很过分
That is a lot to ask.
他拿着一个棕色的文件袋和一些照片
So a brown folder and some photographs.
你知道他走的时候往哪里走了吗?
Did you see which way he went when he left?
他是... 走着还是坐人力车?
Did he... did he walk or take a rickshaw?
我不知道这有没有帮助
Well, I don't know if it helps,
但他说过要是事情顺利的话
but he did say if things went well,
他去德霖路那家店买我最喜欢的蛋糕
he would buy me my favourite cakes from the shop at Teck Lim Road.
就是这家店 温斯顿经常来的
Well, that's the shop, alright. Winston came here all the time.
但她不记得那晚他来了没有
But she can't remember whether he was here that night, though.
已经过去太久了
It's been so long.
- 你还好吗?  - 嗯 我还好
- You alright? - Yeah. I'm alright.
如果他在角落里或者在店外面见的客户
Well, if he met the client at a corner or outside a shop,
那就无踪可寻了
there'd be no trace.
温斯顿有最喜欢的咖啡店或者是餐厅吗?
Did Winston have a favourite kopi shop or restaurant?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
如果他在餐厅或者咖啡店里见的面
If he met inside a restaurant or kopitiam,
没人会记得
no one would remember.
- 德霖路 - 什么?
- Teck Lim Road. - What?
德霖路 工会办公室就在德霖路上
Teck Lim Road. The Trade Union office on Teck Lim Road.
齐基特的办公室 齐基特和温斯顿认识
Chee Kit's office. Chee Kit and Winston knew each other.
- 有可能齐基特就是这个客户 - 有可能
- Perhaps Chee Kit is the client. - It's gotta be.
为什么我要告诉你?
Why should I tell you anything?
你不会有任何损失
You've got nothing to lose.
你弟弟还是想你死
Your brother still wants you dead.
不用考虑我弟弟了
My brother does not concern you.
告诉我 你为谁工作?
But tell me,who do you work for?
帕特丽夏・郑
Patricia Cheng.
你雇佣了她的丈夫 温斯顿
You hired her husband, Winston.
他被杀的那晚你在德霖路的工会办公室
Did you meet with him the night he was killed
和他见过面吗?
at the Trade Union office on Teck Lim Road?
没有 他一直没出现
No. He never turned up.
第二天 我就听说他在一场抢劫中被杀了
And the next day, I heard he was killed in a robbery.
- 你相信吗? - 这也是有可能的
- Do you believe that? - It wasn't impossible.
你在调查谁?
Who were you investigating?
我觉得我弟弟和一些危险人物有关系
I believe my brother was involved with some dangerous people.
我只是想知道
I just wanted to know.
所以你让温斯顿跟踪詹姆士?
So you had Winston follow James?
- 你也不会出现在客户名单上? - 对
- You were never listed as a client? - No.
温斯顿 他有自己的方法
Winston, he had a system.
把我的案子写成不忠的案例
He wrote it up as an infidelity case.
当然 他自己真的有外遇 情况很复杂
Of course, he was actually having an affair, which complicated things,
但我对他的外遇不感兴趣
but I wasn't interested in his affairs with women.
我想知道他跟其他人的会面
I wanted to know about his other meetings.
所以当晚他是去送照片的?
So he was delivering photographs that night?
是的
Yes.
但不知为什么我弟弟发现我在调查他
But somehow my brother found out that I was investigating him.
然后他雇人阻止了温斯顿
And he paid for someone to intercept Winston.
李库方 你认识他吗?
Lee Kum Fong, do you know him?
不认识
No.
那你从没看过任何照片?
So you never saw any photographs?
你也不知道里面有谁?
You don't know who was in them?
不知道
No.
唯一知道真相的人就是我弟弟
The only one who can tell you is my brother,
但他为了保密已经杀过人了
but he has already killed once to keep it secret.
汤米 两杯咖啡
你好
Hello.
你知道有个叫詹姆斯・林的人吗?
What do you know about a guy called James Lim?
康拉德 我知道我们不该来问你
Conrad, I know we shouldn't be asking you,
但我们走投无路了
but we're desperate.
我们实在需要找到杀害郑先生的凶手
We really need to find out who killed Mr Cheng.
如果我们不帮忙 郑太太会十分伤心
Mrs Cheng's miserable and if we don't help her,
她可能会把侦探所关了 然后我就失业了
she might close the agency and then I won't have a job
这样的话我父母就会有理由
and my parents will finally be able to marry me off
把我嫁给某个年轻有为的土生华人了
to some nice young rich Peranakan boy.
我就没法和我心爱的人...
And then I won't be able to go to America...
...一起去美国了
...with the love of my life.
汤米?
Tommy?
你刚才说他老婆很好喝
You told him his wife tastes sweet.
- 这个人叫什么来着? - 詹姆斯・林
- What's this guy's name again? - James Lim.
詹姆斯・林
James Lim.
哈里森 有空跟你说两句吗?
Harrison, you got a minute?
当然啦
Yeah, sure.
听着 我不知道怎样说这件事才好
Look, there's no easy way to say this,
所以我就开门见山好了
so I'm just gonna come right out with it.
月度报告送回总部了
The monthly report's back to HQ.
我建议他们把你安排到别的地方
I'm recommending they post you somewhere else.
为什么?
Why?
有人把机密情报泄露给英国人
Someone's leaking confidential reports to the Brits.
我们跟军情六处互相交换信息啊
Well, we talk to MI6, they talk to us.
我们给的情报他们都已经知道了
We give them stuff that they already know.
除了越南的事
Not on Vietnam.
那份国家安全委员会
That National Security Council report
在周二午餐会议上的报告?
on the Tuesday lunch meetings?
没错
Mm-hmm.
总部只发给了亚洲分部
HQ sent it only to the offices in Asia.
但现在伦敦的人也有了
Now London has it.
那也可能是从别的分部发过去的
Well, that could have come from any of those offices.
但不是的
But it didn't.
重要的不是你这么做了
It's not that you did it.
而是他拿什么威胁你让你这么做的
It's whatever he's got on you that made you do it.
你已经妥协了 我不能用你了
You're compromised. I can't use you.
每个人都有过分的时候 哈里森
Everyone crosses the line, Harrison,
但重要的是 每当你回头看
but it's important when you look back
至少你知道自己在干什么
you can at least still see it.
不管结果怎样 我希望你记住这一点
I hope you remember that, wherever you end up.
- 你好 弗兰克 - 我来跟你决斗
- G'day, Frank. - I came here to fight you.
你在说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
我知道你觉得很荒谬
I'm sure you think that's ridiculous.
但如果这是一个公平的世界
But if this was any sort of just world
有个男人爱着自己的妻子 照顾她
where a man who loved his wife and took care of her
从没想过妻子会背叛自己
and never, ever dreamed of cheating on her,
而另一个男人...
and another man...
如果这是一个公平的世界
If this was any sort of just world,
我会跟你决斗 并打败你
I would fight you and I would beat you.
然而在这个世界 像你这样的男人赢了
In this world, a man like you wins that fight.
像你这样的男人... 怎么了?
A man like you with... what?
你有什么好的能让我老婆选择你?
What have you got that my wife chooses you over me?
周五晚上 我们会永远离开新加坡
Friday night, we're leaving Singapore for good.
我们会乘船去欧洲 再也不回来了
We're going to Europe by ship and we're not coming back.
我理解
I understand.
不 你不理解
No, you really don't.
我要你在我们离开之前去见她
I want you to go to her before we leave.
我要你跟她说清楚
I want you to make your case.
如果你爱着她 想让她一直快乐的话
If you love her in a way that will care for her forever,
你跟她说清楚
you tell her that.
弗兰克 我不会去的...
Frank, I'm not gonna...
如果克莱尔的心还在这儿的话
I'm not gonna spend the rest of my life with Claire
我是不会跟她共度余生的
if part of her never leaves here.
如果她选择了你 那她就跟你走
If she chooses you, she chooses you.
周五晚上之前你还有时间
You've got till Friday night.
- 詹姆斯・林 - 你对他了解有多少?
- James Lim. - What do you know about him?
我以为我们之间已经说清楚了
I thought our arrangement was clear.
当我问你要东西的时候 你就给我
When I ask you for something, I get it.
我不记得还说过要交换条件
I don't recall there being any quid pro quo.
现在不管你跟我老板说什么都不重要了
Right now it doesn't matter what you tell my boss
因为他就要炒掉我了
because he's about to terminate me.
所以我想要你的信息...
So what I need from you...
是想找到他的把柄
I need some dirt on him
这样他们就会炒了他而不是我
so they get rid of him instead of me.
为什么你会特别选择詹姆斯・林?
What made you choose James Lim in particular?
山姆・卡拉汉想要了解他
Sam Callaghan wanted to know about him.
可我去找资料的时候 什么都没有
When I went to look at the file, the file's missing.
唯一能拿到的资料就是... 怀尔德・比尔
The only one with access to that... Wild Bill.
如果他在忙什么...
So if he's up to something...
对啊 他现在忙死了
Oh, yes. He's up to his neck.
这对我来说有什么好处?
But what's in it for me?
华盛顿
Washington.
我没有把安委会文件里的东西都给你
I didn't give you everything that was in that NSC file.
现在 如果你想要给你老板剩下的资料
Now, if you're the guy that tells your bosses the rest,
告诉他们总统办公室里有哪些人
tell them who's in the room with the President,
谁是他的亲信
who's got his ear,
你会拿到本土调动的 我保证
you get that stateside transfer you want, guaranteed.
好啊 成交
Alright. I'm in.
差点忘了 还有一件事
Oh, I almost forgot. There's one more thing.
我要跟苏玲有关的所有资料
I want the files on Su Ling. All copies.
我的天!
My, my!
宝贝小熊真的长大了 对吗?
Baby Bear really has grown up, hasn't he?
哈里森先生来电话了
Mr Harrison called.
说没有詹姆斯・林的资料
He said there was no file on James Lim.
扯淡 詹姆斯・林想要参与政治
That's bullshit. James Lim wants to get into politics.
天啊 他哥哥是被捕的工会领导
For God's sake, his brother's a jailed trade union leader
被指控参与炸弹袭击
accused of bombings.
他们连街上扫地的人的资料都有
They've got files on streetsweepers.
他知道你会这么说
He knew you'd say that.
他说他们没有你想象的那么多情报来源
He said to say they don't have as many tentacles as you think.
我不相信他的话
Well, I don't believe him.
他为什么要撒谎呢?
Why would he lie?
所以整个新加坡
So he's the one man in the whole of Singapore
中情局唯一缺少他的文件?
the CIA doesn't have a file on?
他已经解释啦
Like he said.
阿姨 该停手了
Aunty, it's a sign to stop.
是么 它们只是鸟而已啊
Oh, yeah, they're just birds.
她要的话我随时帮她弄些 还能算便宜点
I can get her some more, for cheap too.
弄只鸭也没问题
Maybe even throw in a duck.
再跟我说下整件事
Explain the whole thing to me again.
温斯顿当时在查詹姆斯・林
Winston was investigating James Lim.
我不知道他查到什么 但已经足以被灭口
I don't know what he found, but it was enough to get him killed.
钥匙 在哪里?
现在可能不太方便上去吧...
Maybe now's not such a good time to...
钥匙 在哪里?
林先生 一切可好?
Everything alright, Mr Lim?
那是李库方吧?
Oh. That was Lee Kum Fong?
他究竟要什么?
What the hell was he after?
我不知道 他刚在喊什么钥匙之类的
I don't know. He was saying something about a key.
喔 喔 算了吧
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Forget it.
他妈的
Come on.
怎么都弄不开这玩意
Never going to get this sucker open.
是啊
Nope.
- 你跟周怡在一块多久了? - 啥?
- How long have you been with Joo Ee? - Huh?
你觉得她就是你要找的吗?
Do you think she's the one?
兄弟 我要一辈子跟她在一起
Uh... I'm with that girl for life, man.
- 是么? - 是啊
-Yeah? - Yeah.
可你们俩就只会吵架啊
All you do is argue.
是啊 她爱喝酒 我爱赌博
Sure. She drinks too much. I gamble too much.
她吼我 我们就打起来了
She yells at me. We fight.
我有的选么?
What's the alternative?
没她的日子 算了吧
A life without her. Forget it, man.
世上只有一个周怡 我喜欢她 就喜欢她一个
There's only one Joo Ee, and I like her. There's nobody else.
妈的
Shit.
我想到了
I got an idea.
康我不懂这个
I don't know about this, Kang.
你觉不觉得我们放太多了?
You don't think we're using too much?
留着用来干嘛?
What else am I going to use this for?
别想太多啦
Yeah, don't think so much.
火灭了 它为什么会灭?
It went out. Why did it go out?
烂导线
Stupid old fuse.
康!
Kang!
康 你还好吗?
Kang, are you alright?
- 啊... - 你还好吧?
- Oh... - You're alright, yeah?
听得到我说话吗?
You hear me?
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
还真炸开了 你个疯子
That opened it, you bloody lunatic.
钱我能留着吧?
I can keep the money, right?
- 反正它们的主人已经死了 - 啥?
- It belongs to a dead man. - Huh?
今天真走运!
Today must be my lucky day.
这肯定是温斯顿的文件
There's no doubt it's Winston's file.
温斯顿叔叔说过
Uncle Winston used to say,
欲速则不达 照片它可不会着急
'No fuss, no rush. The picture won't hurry because you do.'
这张没什么
Nothing here.
- 这张也没有 - 拜托 我们要看到脸
- Nope. This one either. - Come on. We need a face.
下一张看起来有点不同
The next ones look different.
他是...
Is that...
怀尔德・比尔
Wild Bill.
詹姆斯・林... 在和中情局的人秘密会面
James Lim... is having a secret meeting with the CIA.
我不需要 谢谢 谢谢
No, not for me, thank you. Thank you.
康拉德骗了你
Conrad lied to you.
詹姆斯・林是中情局的线人
James Lim's a CIA informant.
一定有他的文件的
There's got to be a file on him.
你肯定找到了的
You must have found it.
- 事情没那么简单 - 就这么简单
- It's not that simple. - Yes, it is.
詹姆斯・林为中情局卖力 对吧?
James Lim works for the CIA, yes or no?
- 不是 - 好吧
- No. - Alright.
我要把所有事告诉阿姆兰
I'm going to take this whole thing to Amran.
新加坡警察对于中情局涉及谋杀
The Singaporean police would be most interested
一个正直的中国良民之事
in the CIA's involvement in the murder
肯定十分感兴趣
of an upstanding Chinese citizen.
詹姆斯・林不是为中情局做事
James Lim did not work for the CIA.
他是为怀尔德・比尔做事
He was working for Wild Bill.
胡说 怀尔德・比尔甚至都不负责那个领域
Bullshit. Wild Bill doesn't even work in the field.
正是 詹姆斯・林就是他的傀儡
Exactly. James Lim was his vanity case.
比尔在办公桌前呆不住 你知道的
Bill hates sitting behind a desk. You know that.
老是说他在别的什么地方
Always talking about being on the ground.
四十五岁时他在东德
45, he was in East Germany.
五十二岁时在和鲁塞尼亚人喝酒
52, he's drinking vodka with the Ruskies.
所以当詹姆斯・林出现时
So, when James Lim walked in,
比尔决定他要亲自秘密操纵詹姆士
Bill decided that he's going to run him himself under the radar.
所以他们就开始秘密会面了
So they start having these secret meetings.
怀尔德・比尔自己做案件记录
Wild Bill's taking all the case notes himself.
- 他们还达成交易 - 什么交易?
- They've got this deal. - What sort of deal?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果中情局想在这里建分局
If the CIA wanted to build a station here,
他们就需要有个新加坡联络人来保护这片土地
they'd need a Singaporean contact to secure the land.
拜托 山姆
Come on, Sam.
如果我知道那情报是真的
If I knew that information to be true,
你真以为我会告诉你吗?
you really think I'd be talking to you about it?
我只知道... 我也是从别人那打听到的
All I know ... and I got this second-hand
詹姆斯・林去见怀尔德・比尔
is that James Lim went to see Wild Bill
是因为他觉得有个私家侦探在跟踪他
because he thought a private investigator was following him,
而且可能还拍了他们一起的照片
and there may be some photos of them together.
然后呢? 怀尔德・比尔做了什么?
And? What did Wild Bill do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我真不知道
I don't.
那份文件不见了
The file's gone missing.
被人毁了
Someone destroyed it.
我们走吧
Let's go.
卡拉汉 你也玩五百吗?
You play 500, Callaghan?
我玩另一个游戏
I've had a game.
绅士的游戏
A gentleman's game.
不像扑克
Not like poker.
扑克是给粗人玩的
Poker's for assholes.
是你杀了温斯顿・郑吗?
Did you kill Winston Cheng?
没有 妈的 没有
No. Shit no.
当然不是我
Of course not.
不是
No.
林告诉你
Lim had told you there'd been
有人拍了你俩在一块的照片
photographs taken of the two of you together.
对我而言 这没什么 我们是中情局的
It meant nothing to me. We're the CIA.
我们有很多线人 他是其中之一 这没什么
We have informants. He was one of them. Big deal.
就算登在也不关我事
Publish them in The Straits Times for all I care.
告诉所有人中情局正在秘密买地
Tell everyone the CIA is buying up land on the quiet
建立秘密工作基地?
to build a covert operational base?
不是好事 但我可以否认
Not great, but deniable.
- 不是为了詹姆斯・林 - 不是
- Not for James Lim. - No.
他吓得要死
He was freaking out.
他想从政
He wants to get into politics.
和美国佬串通可不是什么好事
Not a good idea to be in bed with the Yanks,
不过是他的问题 与我无关
but... his problem, not mine.
所以他雇了方去杀温斯顿?
So he hired Fong to kill Winston?
我原是这么想的
That's what I thought.
直到今天
Until today.
谁杀了林?
Who had Lim killed?
还有别的事
And there's something else.
显而易见 某个人 某个耍纸牌的混蛋
Apparently, someone, some poker-playing asshole,
一直在深究
has been doing some digging,
发现了我都不知道的事
found out something even I didn't know about.
什么事?
What's that?
詹姆斯・林有个沉默的同伙
James Lim has a silent partner.
- 有人在幕后资助他 - 是谁?
- Somebody's bankrolling him. - Who?
高层不愿透露
Head office won't say.
但他们肯定坏极了 因为 不管是谁
But they must be real bad, because, whoever it is,
我也被牵扯其中
my involvement with them,
即使是通过林这么一个第三方
even through a third party like Lim,
也足以让我被遣送出局了
is enough to get me shipped out of here.
中情局和什么人都有往来
There's not too many people the CIA won't do business with.
俄罗斯人? 北越南人?
The Russians? North Vietnamese?
我倒想知道
I'd love to know.
无论谁 他们肯定有钱
Whoever it is, they've got the money
资助詹姆斯・林的地产贸易
to bankroll James Lim's land deals.
还能保释方出狱
And to bail Fong out of jail.
也会为保守秘密而杀掉任何人
And they'll kill anyone to keep their involvement secret.
只要找出这个人 就能找出谁杀了温斯顿
You find out who that is, you find out who murdered Winston.
可是 卡拉汉...
But, Callaghan...
...确保在他们发现你之前找到他们
...make sure you find them before they find you.
山姆 你不会相信这个
Sam, you won't believe this.
他进来的时候我正在看文件
I was looking at these documents when this man broke in.
- 刚开始我还以为是你 - 不 这就是方
- At first I thought it was you. - No, that's Fong alright.
毫无疑问他杀了温斯顿
And there's no doubt he killed Winston.
所以他们杀温斯顿是因为这条信息
So they killed Winston for this information.
我发现凯・索和詹姆斯・林
What I found out was that Kay Song and James Lim
共事好多年 收买地产
had been in partnership for years, buying up land.
凯・索?
Kay Song?
可是红龙绝对不会和中情局搅合到一起
But the Red Dragons would never be in bed with the CIA.
凯・索单独行动的 猛虎将军不知道
Kay Song is on his own. The Tiger General doesn't know.
如果这就是凯・索的秘密...
If that's Kay Song's secret...
...凭这点就可以抓到他了
...that's how we get him.
如果猛虎将军知道他的孙子和中情局有瓜葛
If the Tiger General knew his grandson was in bed with the CIA,
他会杀了他的
he'd kill him.
- 你肯定? - 绝对肯定
- Are you sure of this? - Absolutely.
如果不这么做 凯・索会一直派人追踪我们
If we don't, Kay Song will keep sending people after us.
你 我 和苏玲
You, me, Su Ling.
我恳请跟杜凯见面
I respectfully seek an audience with Toh Kay.
我们不想惹麻烦
Look, we don't want any trouble.
这有关于杀害我丈夫温斯顿・郑的凶手
This is about the murder of my husband, Winston Cheng.
女士 这不是你该来的地方
Woman, this is not your place.
别动她!
Hey, leave her alone!
来人呐！
Somebody help!
快来人！
Somebody!
你孙子骗了你
Your grandson is cheating you.
他有秘密进账
He has secret accounts.
他有私房钱
He has secret money.
他在为自己工作
He's working for himself.
我要听听他们的话
I will hear them.
给自己做棺材 真是个好传统
It is a good tradition, making one's own coffin.
我们的习惯是在派上用场好多年之前就做好
It is our custom to do so many years before it is needed.
为死亡准备亦即为生命准备
To be prepared for death is to be prepared for life.
你们国家有这种传统吗?
Do you have this custom in your country?
应该有
You should.
一个到处出漏子的人
A man who blunders here and there
可能比想象得更早用上棺材
may need a coffin sooner than he thinks.
说吧
Speak.
不是你
Not you.
你和这个人在一起干什么?
What are you doing with this man?
我和许多人都见过面啊
I have meetings with a lot of people.
- 做生意的 家族领袖 - 私房钱呢?
- Businessmen, clan leaders. - Secret money?
买片便宜地卖给美国人
For buying cheap land to sell to the Americans.
-我们就要赚钱了 - 美国人?!
- We were going to make a fortune. - Americans?!
是中情局
The CIA.
我们控制着这座岛 一百多年了
For over 100 years, we controlled this island.
别人自以为有权有势
Others think they have the power.
可他们来了又走
But they come, they go.
英国人在这儿一个世纪 不也走了
The British, here for a century, they go too.
这座岛终于是我们的了
Finally we have this island to ourselves.
你还帮美国人掌权
And you help the Americans take power.
我是为了你
I did it for you.
你是为了自己
You did it for yourself.
为了钱
For money.
结束了
It's over.
不要给我看
别让我看见尸体
Do not let me see the body.
傻孩子
You stupid boy.
你以为你能把我们全杀了?
You think you can kill us all?
这倒是坚定了我的决心
This thinking confirms my decision.
不 是坚定了我的
No. It confirms mine.
像你这么老的人...
An old man like you...
年老体衰
So frail, so weak.
你疯了 我还能活很多年
You're mad. I have many years in me.
可能会 可能不会
Maybe. Maybe not.
你们走吧
You may leave.
我爷爷心脏病突发
My grandfather had a heart attack.
我们有证人
We have witnesses.
把这噩耗告诉我们的人吧
Go tell our people the bad news.
很抱歉你们目睹了这个令人悲伤的时刻
I'm sorry you had to be here for this sad day.
郑夫人 山姆
Mrs Cheng, Sam.
现在让我一个人沉浸在悲痛中吧
You may now leave me to my grief.
请进
Come in.
你想见我 先生
You wanted to see me, sir.
我会很愿意永远不见你
I'd happily never set eyes on you again.
不过当权者自作聪明
But the powers that be, in their wisdom,
决定冻结所有的调动
have decided to put a freeze on all transfers.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
好像我才该是那个评审的人吧
It seems my position's the one up for review.
我不知道你做了什么 对谁亏欠
I don't know what you did or who you owe.
但是记住... 和狗睡 就得忍着跳蚤
But remember this... you lay down with dogs, you get up with fleas.
你按照你的方式行事 先生
Well, you played the game your way, sir.
和詹姆斯・林 进行土地贸易
With James Lim, with the land deal.
我只不过做了该做的
I just did what I had to do.
我所做的 都是为了这个组织为了我的祖国
Everything I did, I did for this organisation and for my country.
如果他们解雇我... 当然 会很伤心
If they sack me... sure, it'll hurt.
不过我可以每天照镜子
But I can look in the mirror every day.
你觉得你照镜子会怎么样 哈里森?
What do you see when you look in the mirror, Harrison?
因为总有一天 也许不是今天 不是明天
'Cause one day, maybe not today, not tomorrow,
但是总有一天那玩意儿会把你活吞了
but one day that thing is going to eat you alive.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
你说对了一件事
Oh. You're right about one thing.
不是今天
Not today.
米勒少校
Major Miller.
我刚收到电报
I just got the telegram.
我下个月去华盛顿
I'm off to Washington next month.
这是唯一的副本了?
This is the only copy?
我们有交易的
We had a deal.
你坚持你的原则 我坚持我的
You kept up your end. I kept up mine.
也许我会在华盛顿见你
Maybe I'll see you in Washington.
总有一天
One day.
很可能
Good chance.
希望她值得你这么做
I hope she's worth it.
来来来 大家来喝一杯 开心点 来
温斯顿是我们的好朋友
温斯顿是个好男人
Winston is a good man.
哎呀夫人 你不要太过悲伤 放轻松下 过来
你讲啦
哎呀你是他老婆
今天中秋 中秋是个
...合家团圆的日子
...is for family,
你们就像我的家人一样
and you are like family to me.
事实上 你们是我唯一的家人了
As a matter of fact, you are the only family I have.
所以 谢谢你们
So, thank you.
我讲什么
喝酒喝酒
我曾努力设想过温斯顿会说什么
Well, I tried to imagine what Winston would say,
然后我意识到他不过是整晚
and I realise he'd just be drinking
喝酒跳舞讲笑话
and dancing and joking all night long,
所以今晚我希望你们也这么做
so this is what I want you to do tonight.
# 我这颗心脏已经被伤了一千次 #
Ooh, this old heart of mine been broke a thousand times
# 每次你离开我都以为你会留下来 #
Each time you break away I think you're gone to stay
# 孤独的夜晚让记忆流淌 #
Lonely nights that come Memories that flow
# 把你带回来一次次地伤害我 #
Bringing you back again Hurting me more and more
# 也许向你表达我内心的爱是个错误 #
Maybe it's my mistake to show this love I feel inside
# 因为日子一天天过去 #
'Cause each day that passes by
# 因为你我从来不知道该何去何从 #
You've got me never knowin' if I'm comin' or goin', but I
# 不过我爱你 #
I love you-ou-ou
# 这颗老去的心 亲爱的 是为你而伤 #
This old heart, darling, is weak for you
# 我爱你 #
I love you-ou-ou
# 是的 我爱你 是的 我爱你 #
Yes, I do. Yes, I do
# 我这残老的手臂怀念你的拥抱 #
These old arms of mine miss having you around
# 催下我内心的热泪 #
Makes these tears inside start falling down
# 你用一个残缺的吻 #
Always with half a kiss
# 提醒我错失的一切 #
you remind me of what I miss
# 虽然我努力控制自己 #
Though I try to control myself
# 我却像傻瓜一样咧嘴而笑 #
Like a fool I start grinnin'
# 因为我的大脑已经开始眩晕 #
Cause my head starts spinnin' 'cause I
# 因为我爱你 #
I love you-ou-ou
# 这颗老去的心 亲爱的 是为你而伤 #
This old heart, darling, is weak for you.
# 我爱你 #
I love you-ou.
# 是的 我爱你 是的 我爱你 #
Yes, I do Yes, I do.
# 我努力隐藏我内心的伤 #
Ooh, I try hard to hide my hurt inside.
# 这颗老去的心不停哭泣... #
This old heart of mine always keeps me cryin'...
对不起我对你撒谎了
I'm sorry that I lied to you.
也许我只是... 我太想跟你在一起了
I guess I just... I wanted to be with you so badly
所以我不知道该怎么做才能实现愿望
that I lost sight of what I was doing to get there,
要是你不想跟我说话... 我也理解
and I understand if you don't want to talk to me...
没关系
that's OK.
我只想让你知道我不知道是谁杀了温斯顿・郑
I just needed you to know that I had no idea who killed Winston Cheng.
我知道
I know.
山姆全查出来了
Sam found out everything.
郑先生的死跟中情局无关
Mr Cheng's death had nothing to do with the CIA.
康拉德 我明白也接受
Conrad, I know and accept
你不能把工作上的事都告诉我
that you can't tell me everything about your job,
但我向你问问题的时候
but if I ask you a question
是想要一个诚实的答案
I expect an honest answer.
或者说"无可奉告"就可以了
Or just say, 'No comment.'
无可奉告
No comment.
"无可奉告" 别说谎
'No comment.' Don't lie.
- 我得确定我能信任你 - 你可以信任我
- I need to know that I can trust you. - You can.
我们努力来实现吧
Then let's try to make this work.
送给你的
I got you this.
谢谢
Thank you.
小心点吧 你个臭小子
Take that, you little piece of shit.
# 我放下我的尊严 #
I swallowed my pride
# 我祈求你祈求你 #
And I beg I beg of you
# 宝贝 请不要再让我为你流泪 #
Oh, baby, stop these tears that you are putting me through.
# 请读一下我的信 #
Please read my letter.
# 你为什么不逐行逐句地读...? #
Why don't you read every line...?
有时候 我能感受到他的手在我的发间
Sometimes, I can literally feel his hand in my hair.
就像一个梦 直到我醒来
Like in a dream, except I'm awake.
你一晚上都在想她
You've been thinking about her all night.
# 这是我最后一封信了 宝贝 #
This is my last letter, baby
# 亲爱的 这就是告别... #
Oh, darling, this is goodbye...
去找她吧
Go to her.
# 你知道 我不需要照片 #
You see, I need no picture
# 来让我记住你 #
To remind me of you
# 还有我与你共度的这些美好时光 #
Oh, and all these wonderful moments that I have spent here with you
# 所以 我放下我的尊严 #
So, I swallowed up my pride
# 我祈求你 我祈求你 #
And I beg, I beg, I beg of you
# 宝贝 为什么你还不停下来...? #
Oh, baby, why don't you stop now...?
- 克莱尔 - 山姆
- Claire. - Sam.
我们能谈谈吗?
Can we talk?
我来收拾行李
I'll finish packing the luggage.
你该跟他谈谈
You should talk to him.
- 克莱尔 等等 - 你来干什么?
- Claire, wait. - What are you doing here?
- 留下来吧 - 留下来?
- Stay. - Stay?
我爱你 克莱尔
I'm in love with you, Claire.
我以前从没有爱过一个人
I've never loved anyone before.
你知道这对我来说意味着什么吗?
Do you have any idea what it's been like for me?
我不知道你已经告诉弗兰克了
I didn't know you'd told Frank.
你为什么不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
因为你已经说清楚了
Because you made it very clear
跟我在一起的生活太艰难太压抑太...
that life with me was too hard or cramped or...
我以为我在做正确的事
I thought I was doing the right thing.
什么正确的事?
How?
大家都在背后嘲笑我的时候
How were you doing the right thing
你把我留在塔克沃思家
by leaving me at the Tuckworths',
这就是正确的事?
everyone sniggering at me behind their back?
我... 对不起
I... I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道你很抱歉 看看你的脸
I know you are. Look at your face.
不要走
Don't go.
现在是什么情况?
So what happens now?
我们得把你的行李从车上卸下来
Well, we've got to get your luggage out of the car.
然后呢?
And then?
然后我们回到我家
And then we go back to my place.
我们吃点面条和辣椒螃蟹
We get noodles and some chilli crab.
我们来点月饼
We get mooncake.
今天是中秋节
It's the Festival of the Moon.
看月亮升到空中 再看着它落下
Watch the moon rise, then watch it set.
我再也不会让你离开了
I'll never let you go again.
这比我想象的还要美妙
It sounds more wonderful than I can imagine.
- 先生 到时间了 - 好的
- Uh, sir, it's time. - Yes.
那明天呢?
What about tomorrow?
我们会解决的
We'll work it out.
太晚了 山姆
It's too late, Sam.
我爱你
I love you.
我永远爱你
And I will always love you.